welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
okay so it's just some check-ins do you
wanna you want to go first sure I'm
feeling a little anxious it's it's an
anxiety that's sort of like coming in
and going out it's like a like a wave
moving in and out in and I have a pretty
solid movement practice that is pretty
reliable in moving that anxiety but I've
just sort of I'm making peace at the
fact that that like that latent anxiety
I think is normal under the given
circumstances hmm you know like two
weeks to expect to feel grounded and
happy and confident and energized all
the time amidst like the current moment
of uncertainty I think is like that pill
that feels like a pipe dream right
though so like making friends with the
anxiety and fear I think is tip to me a
better move than trying to make it go
away all the time yeah I like that and
also kind of like um but I got from that
is like the the judgment that's there
about it and it's like also making
friends with that judgment totally
totally yeah there's like the there's
like the feeling bad and then there's a
fork in the road and it's you could you
can either have anxiety about feeling
bad and disassociate and I sort of find
your escape route and sometimes that's
fine like watching TV all day like
whatever like people that's gonna happen
and then the other move is to be curious
about the experience and actually move
to find the physiological correlate to
the anxiety because it's usually
information for you yes hundred percent
like I I'm starting to view emotional
states as like friends giving you advice
but sometimes friends don't always give
you the best advice but they're coming
from a good place
so
best to listen to them and translate
them and whatever yeah and then looking
to mind that that term from acceptance
commitment therapy I think it's from
that dirty pain versus clean pain we're
like what's the difference so clean pain
is like you know you you're injured
you're hurt like a loved one died
someone breaks up with you it hurts
hurts right but dirty pain is like
having that judgment on the pain so it's
like it's like doubly painful because
you have a thing then you judge yourself
and so there's a pain from the judgment
and then the dirty pain kind of like
makes it last and it like makes it
pathological right
it's like compound interest on your pain
yeah a guy has this as a kid so I'll do
a check-ins now definitely my check-in
now would be different than if I were to
start if I would have just started this
session with the check-in yeah I feel
kind of good now there's like a
lightness at doing that little exchange
with you I was feeling sort of
fragmented a little bit a little bit
scattered and skittish that had it's
calming down and I'm sort of being like
cold into your energy maybe there's like
I'm just I'm projecting maybe here's
something like I feel like there's
there's something here that I want to
not be pulled by excellent yeah I'm
already feeling a lot calmer just entry
into this conversation amazing what
fucking communication could I know I
know
so yeah message on Twitter spontaneously
like hey Colin come on the stove podcast
let's talk about the existential dance
party for those who are listening right
now who may not be familiar with it
Colin is doing a regular session like
every Thursday now at 7:30 p.m. Eastern
Time this week's gonna be 8:30 Eastern
Time
and I'll let you explain the kind of
with the practitioner the psycho tech is
but I guess yeah yeah it'll and I wanted
to talk to you about that kind of like
kind of you know flesh shadow and get to
know your role a little bit more but
maybe I can just share some thoughts
about how that came about
Oh dance party and I'll kind of hand
over to you how that kind of like how
you see it evolving and what's your
relationship with it so uh the idea of
the store I kind of want this to be like
a psycho incubator for psycho technology
and then maybe some kind of wisdom chimp
and form from it and I'm just allowing
the what I call the daemon just to kind
of guide me and then they're called like
Colin I was always a I was on Colin's
podcast that I own 2.0 and he was like
kicking ass with gasps I'm like ah man
pawns like you know he's like rising in
the sense-making world with his his lip
podcast and he started dancing on
Twitter and I'm like this is odd hey who
is this guy like dude he's dead like
it's just like it was to two different
like you punk a Colin's a sense maker
podcast he's not supposed to be dancing
on Twitter let me be I was just lightly
jealous because his dance moves are
pretty like it's pretty good and uh I
don't know a dance or at least I don't
think I know how to dance and then I
just had this intuition when I launched
a project of the stolen I'm like hey
Colin do you want to do some kind of
dance kind of exercise and body man type
of stuff on the stove test it out and
then we workshopped it real quickly and
then the term existential dance party
emerged and there were two sessions in
and it's like to me is that one of my
favorite times of the week so far no so
yeah so woody what do you think of and
you know mmhmm yeah I was really I was
really excited when you when you asked
me to to help prototype something with
you because I've been finding that the
more the longer that I've done this
podcast the more
it's kind of bringing me back to my body
like I used to be an actor and that was
that was my work for many years before I
started syan to point out and it's all
about embodiment I mean to be to be a
compelling actor to be a truth teller on
stage you really do have to step inside
this character shoes and understand
their internal life but it's not like
you don't under you never understand
understand yourself as an individual
it's always in relation to another
person even if it's a one-man show it's
a relationship with different parts of
yourself so there's like this embodied
relational quality to a lot of the the
work that I've explored in my life and
[Music]
I'm I love I
I ideas it's so fun
I love nerding out on different topics
and I was just sort of finding that I
was sort of losing myself in in the
ideas and losing connection to my actual
embodied existence and fee and and I
guess having difficulty applying some of
the concepts that we were talking about
on this podcast and we've had a lot of
the same guests and it's it's it's it's
about sense making it's about it's about
the meta-crisis it's about the future
where we're headed where we're going
what can we do and I just started to ask
myself really seriously what I what I
can do and what sort of my my day mon
like wants to be expressing on a day to
day basis and I realized that I needed
to be moving my body a lot more than I
was in order to sense make effectively
and I I mean I think everyone could be
moving more but but but there is
something about like my particular
Constitution that is very body first
like body focused and that's how I get
[Music]
that's I feel like where where my
intelligence wants to express primarily
and then the ideas can come after and so
when I started date when I just sort of
sort of started putting dance videos on
Twitter it was a way for me to
experiment with how to bridge these to
bridge these two worlds or basically
just put something put a signal out
there and see if it was interesting to
people and the thing that I really like
about this existential dance party and
where I think it's going is that it's
not about it's not performative mmm it's
not about me posting a video like like
look at this like cool flow like look at
this cool dance move that I am doing
it's more about the relational practice
and that's really what I want it to be
about but that's what I want
embodiment to be about for me it is that
relational quality is that sense of like
what what does it look like when a bunch
of people have that experience together
and what what changes in the space
because of that and like how do you
think we didn't really talk about like
debrief or how you thought how you
thought those sessions went cuz I
thought they went extremely well
especially the last one like I just I
said it in a few different places now
that like you needed exercise and you
all calls playlists on Spotify by the
way so if you want to like listen to
them
the last song you did when you no put
your hand in your heart and your hand
your gut and then you just like stare to
everyone on the screen like I felt
really really tender and kind of
connected there especially after all
that movement so I'm curious two things
I'm curious like like how do they go for
you at the first two and like how did
you go about designing them like
hmm yeah the second one I felt like was
a huge improvement on the first one
which is to be expected the first one I
had no idea what it was gonna be but the
second one actually just gave me a
bigger sense of what I wanted the
container to be starting out with
stillness on either end and using that
opportunity to
basically have stillness be the
barometer for the beginning and and so
you actually have space to check in and
see what changed right
because I'll because dancing moves so
much energy and sometimes you're not
even a symptoms you're not even
consciously aware what's happening which
I think is okay that it sort of gets
back to what I was talking about the
story piece like sometimes in in the
cognitive behavioral therapy for example
it often starts with the story first the
meaning making first that comes from the
mind and a really skilled therapist can
help deconstruct that story as the
process goes forward but the thing that
I think is really useful about moving
first is you're actually checking into
other pieces of information that your
system has to offer so emotional
emotions are often stuck in the body
that's like there's all this research
and trauma where like if if an animal
gets hit by a car like a deer for
example and isn't killed it'll
immediately start shaking and it's just
to release the tension that was created
in that impact and and I think we we can
do that intuitively but oftentimes we
don't know that that's a capacity that
we have and if you're going with the
story first and you don't move that
energy you can start creating all these
belief systems around that stuckness
rather than actually just being aware of
it moving it and then seeing what comes
out on the other side the story will be
completely different
hmm seems like there's so much different
with what you just said there's so much
different ways to experiment especially
like adding reintegrating the cognitive
component yeah so this is something I
want to talk to you about in this
conversation is I've been I've been
listening to a lot of conversations
you've been having on the stoah and one
of the one of the threads that I think I
picked up with John Revathi and both
John and Zach Stein is this idea of
ritual and I think it's connected to
what John said about stealing the
culture and I'm I've just been thinking
about this all week of what kind of what
kind of ritual can we intentionally
create in the context of this dance
party and it doesn't have to be
elaborate it doesn't have to be super
mythopoetic but something that's a
little bit more intentional than just
starting with stillness and bringing
awareness to different parts of the body
like be like I'm wanting to be a little
more creative with that that ritual yeah
it was coming to mind and this might be
like feel free to swap this away or
whatever but it might be a seed here
some aspect of it is you know Andrew
tiger the guy who kind of influenced my
kind of philosophical trajectory he
always talks about the question that is
has has the most existential weight or
is most extra-specially salient and he
views philosophy is not sort of you know
dialoguing about all these abstract
issues is it's what is most relevant in
your life that connects with the mind
and the heart so in his philosophical
practice is always about the person you
know like you know like starting like
reasoning from their issue that is as
most alive for them so I'm wondering if
there's something that could be present
there about like present seeing the
question that is the most alive for you
or most existentially salient and then
maybe an answer might come come through
dancing or something like that yeah yeah
yeah
yeah I like that have the question lead
the movement yeah have you seen the oh
way do you know that show no it's a
Netflix show and there's this I don't
want to talk too much about I just
couldn't want to point to this one
sequence there's this some really
interesting way that they explore
movement and synchronicity and it's sort
of a sci-fi type show and there's this
the main character this woman has access
to these codes and the codes are
expressed through movement and the only
way to access the let's say the
intelligence of this particular code
sequence is for I think six people to do
this this series of movements at the
same time with the same intention not
thinking but just like really dropping
into the flow of the experience right
and and that's actually something that
many cultures have explored throughout
history like the Sufis have this
tradition the the whirling dervishes
they're called and if you just google or
look up on YouTube the whirling
dervishes they induce this ecstatic
trance like experience by basically
spinning and focusing their attention
upward and they're all spinning in
unison and and they they move like this
for very long periods of time and they
receive information from this experience
and it might depend on the individual
what information is moving through them
but by entering into this communal
experience by connecting your movement
to the group and by connecting your
intention to communing with God
in some way you who are going to receive
something some new piece of information
that you wouldn't have received before
you entered into this experience right
so it blends ritual it blends movement
it blends communitas and it blends the
sort of religious experience of ecstasy
so what's what's coming to mind right
now hearing you say this and then going
back to that suggestion about having a
question it seems to individual based
you know because everyone can have
different questions with different
energies and then what was very sweet
and tender about the last exercise with
dance party especially when we were
staring at each other was that you know
this the same emotions were coming up I
could I could feel it where all this in
the same music and so it had that sort
of community toss feel to it and what
came to mind is there's a session I'm
doing on Sunday with this FileMaker cafe
is a heady he's one of my favorite
filmmakers she's things is really really
radical radically honest and that a
filmmaker and so we're doing something
called making friends with fear and so
like imagine a zoom call these these
faces and then we're all gonna presents
fear because that's kind of like a
universal emotion that's happening right
now and then we're gonna all feel it and
then come what comes to mind when we
feel it and then we're going to
everyone's gonna have like a one-minute
share about what they're afraid of
right and then at the end we're gonna
charlie make friends with fear like
collectively do some kind of meta
loving-kindness meditation to fear
itself and I kind of like that like
building relationships with her in
states so I wonder how like like maybe
fear dancing or anger dancing you know
like yeah getting really into that
motion collectively with people yeah
totally I started to experiment with
that a little bit in the last one with
that that say anything song yeah alive
and the glory of love I think is what
the song is called
it's like kind of this punk rock defiant
song and that felt a really potent and
there's also this question of not
necessarily wanting to
[Music]
project a certain emotional state on
somebody if that's not what they're
going through so I'm kind of holding
that that tension of really wanting to
explore the fruit of diving deep into a
particular emotional state and how that
dance wants to express itself hmm well
at the same time just sort of letting
whatever comes up naturally happen for
the individual a mover or dancer there
might be something to structuring one
existential dance party and in
structuring it and a little bit more of
an intentional way and saying that
we will be priming everyone
to move through these different
emotional states and if you feel like
you you're interested in surrendering to
that experience like it's here for you
and if that feels a little too edgy or
uncomfortable like maybe sit this one
out just like being a little bit more
upfront about what the thing is right
yeah and what I'm appreciating about you
right now
and and it's this it's building trust
like more trust toward that I have
towards you is is I can tell the
discernment that you're having right
here you're being very considerate
because if you you set a frame to
strongly just could bias the whole
experience and could like defeat the
purpose of what the dang one is asking
of you right now so I see a nimble
Astaire and I would know which I'm
appreciating in this building trust yeah
yeah yeah this um I think what you're
doing with the stoah is really inspiring
it's the exploratory nature of it and
the the whole gift economy overlay on
top of it I think is really really cool
and I I was thinking about
what what would be possible to do
something similar but having it be all
about movement and just inviting
different movement teachers and leaders
on four different sessions like doesn't
doesn't John Burbank II do Tai Chi yes
like if I John wanted to lead a Tai Chi
workshop have somebody do a yoga
workshop have like I'm friends with one
of Edo portals main students and have
someone lead like a IDO portal style mmm
and culture exercise and it could be and
have it be like a very similar sort of
framing like the stoah has but have it
be more explicitly be about movement
yeah I think that I think that could be
so cool so that's funny that you
mentioned that because the the idea that
came to mind when I felt into your Damon
and the actual special dance party is
like a digital dance studio that has
sort of a spiritual feel or
philosophical feel to it and it
basically is just exactly what you
described like this ion movement
whatever design movement collective yeah
like that could be a digital dance
studio right that like you you Stuart
like I'm Stuart in the stoah but it's
like it features all these different
facilitators I can operate on something
like the gift economy - yeah yeah how is
the gift economy model working so far
like what do you have different
relationships with it at different times
or does it are you just trusting the
whole thing right now well it's sort of
like like I mentioned like my and Winton
Brett invite Andrew on because that's
where I got the inspiration from and
he's been operating on the gift economy
over five years support his livelihood
all that type of stuff with all of his
like all of his offerings that he
everything all gift economy yeah for his
for his philosophical counseling I think
he tried to do kind of like a consulting
business but it didn't really fly but
yeah and once he hit like some some
articles got released on him visit
started some of his conversational
partners were in Silicon Valley so they
had a lot of influence and money and so
he started getting the gift started
getting more so
I don't want to get into his details but
you know worked out well for him and
I've hosted like hundreds of events here
in Toronto for free I charged for one
conference and you know I just enjoyed
it I was like Damon inspired and now I
brought the stuff online because the
Cova we can't meet in person and it
doesn't feel right to charge money right
even though I think a lot of people need
money or finances but it feels really
right to present this as a gift because
it does feel like this is my greatest
gift to the world right now
right I had the oxygen mask on I got my
wife and parents like a prepper stuff
behind me I hope you can't see too much
of it so I feel pretty pretty good with
that area for now so now it's like
turning to the question what could be my
highest gift to the world and it really
feels like it's a stola but it's kind of
like and I but it feels really right
receiving gifts if people are inspired
to give it to me and so hence I have the
gift economy at the bottom of the page
and people have been giving me gifts
they've been having they've been giving
me gifts in the form of money they'd be
giving me gifts in the form of like
support like I got this badass intro on
my video now is thanks for someone to
for doing a video editor who did that
someone gifted me to get any courses I
got like this this hunting like four-day
hunting experience in Texas for you to
teach you how to like hunt and got an
animal then you go around the fire right
it was like like okay like I'll do it if
I can like I can send it to item was not
coming to my room
yeah he might be part of our scene yeah
but yeah that's like cool and then so
and then I'll share this like so I'm
like on all-hands-on-deck with this I've
been like you know just so focused on
the store right now but I took a break a
couple days ago
and watched that and nuke I rich he
moved me a movie with my wife and I used
the gift money from PayPal to pay for it
and then when I paid for it I swear to
god man is like I think a ray of light
just kind of shined on me from it and it
just felt like like like oh like the
world just gave me a gift or something
it just felt like so pure and I never
felt that way before ever
like purchasing anything it's something
huh so andrew is onto something here
with this this gift economy thing that's
awesome I love that yeah I think I might
have to have Andrew my podcast to you to
talk about gift economy dynamics I'm so
intrigued by it I think it's brilliant
it feels like game B before game B was
even around type thing yeah
such a such and exercised and Trust and
surrender yeah and so like circling back
to the digital we call dance studio and
your name like Zion I don't know if this
was intentional on your part but what
comes to mind when I think of Zion isn't
seen in the matrix to where everyone's
was dancing like you know wildly
hedonistic dancing and they're like and
I think tour in Zion there was there any
connection there is that just uh yeah so
there there are a lot of connections
with the Zion
so one of them I mean one of them is the
matrix because I'm just a huge fan of
that movie I was a very impactful movie
when I watched it for the first time but
then I also I grew up Mormon until I was
nine and Mormons have a huge connection
to Zion like the Zion is there like
freedom utopia Promised Land place right
and then the Rastas have the
relationship with Zion too and the Jews
have a relationship design it basically
is like utopia freedom liberation and
when I started the podcast at two point
no to me meant like what if Zion is an
unfolding process and so if there's a
2.0 there can be a 3.0 4.0 and that
there's not a static Promised Land it's
not a finished destination it's it's a
it's a constantly unfolding process I
like that it's like what came to mind
was that that Ken Wilber quote the best
series the one that gets you the next
it's like the best Promised Land is the
one I get you the next yeah easily so it
doesn't like fossilized and become like
you know fundamental whatever yeah
that's cool
and and I think that's what I'm that's
what ideology can do is it can become a
calcified promised land it it can give
you this sort of existential comfort
great until that moment where it gets
poked in just the right way and it all
comes crumbling down and it's on you to
figure out the next promised land what's
what are the next questions that you
have to ask in order to get yourself out
of bed
yes yeah I like that a lot and this is
why I kind of really want to frame the
stoah as a project that's meant to die
because I don't want to get too eco ugly
attached to it because you know it's
like I'm moving full steam all this kind
of like sexy stuffs coming out of it and
like I was getting attention on Twitter
and stuff like that and then you know
you get those ego hits but it's like I
don't wanna get too attached to it in
that sense like I want to be really high
fidelity with where the Damon is asking
me to go but I don't want to have that
thing where this becomes the Promised
Land you know my promised land yeah
totally yeah and so like your podcast
design a 2.0 I think I was like one of
your your first guests or one of the
earlier guess I should say and I used to
been like kicking ass with it just like
think it's a shroud alexander bard and i
kind of liked the guest selection
because you know you kind of feel into
the the meta space where it's like
Daniel Sorensen he has sort of like kind
of emerging the emerging leaders right
like what's the future he pivoted more
to like psycho technologies recently you
know rebel wisdom is more like the kind
of that almost a culture war
conversation with like intellectual dark
web to the game be stuff future thinkers
has sort of like a futuristic vibe and
there's like a sort of uh it's the same
kind of same sense making web but
they're like different kind of
characters but I feel a kinship with
yours the guests that you have on
because they're like there's an eclectic
miss there and there's like there's a
theme but I'm not not a theme and yeah
this is this is
yeah I wanted to bring up like I
mentioned this in our conversation we
had with Jared Snyder that you know Tim
and I don't a since Nider Jerry James
and Tim from voice craft that that tweet
you did about the keygen levels and then
saying what's the keygen level where you
stop giving a shit about keygen levels
when I first saw that see I'm like pass
it you know that's he nailed it writing
he named what needed to be named right
there
because I feel like you and I both have
that and I imagine all these other
people to space the meta tribe has it as
well
so yeah I won't I wouldn't even bother
asking questions to see what comes up
for you yeah yeah I feel like we all go
through different different seasons of
life where we're drawn to a particular
meme our personality is being expressed
in a certain way based on the sorts of
ideas or people that were surrounding
ourselves with and I can look back and
see that my life goes through very
distinct chapters where I think the way
that Keegan puts it in his levels is
there's more of a passive section where
you're you're just sort of listening and
receiving and then more of an active
chapter of each level and the activists
were you're more engaged in a world and
sort of making concrete decisions based
on maybe the information that you
learned from the passive receiving part
but for me rather than passive active it
feels more like serious and humorous
sometimes I go through periods where I
take myself so seriously and like the
ideas are just like so important so
important you know and there's like this
freedom and lusus and lightness when I'm
able to relax and let that seriousness
go I love the way that I think Zac said
it on your it was either yours or Andrew
Sweeney's podcast recently he was saying
like
[Music]
there's a humor or a sense of humor that
comes on the other side of tragedy it's
like this transcendental humor right you
know it's not it's not this maybe it's
kind of it kind of relates that will
bury in like pre trans fallacy like
maybe humor that is um a little too
cutting maybe it's mean maybe it's it
it's like sort of compensating for
something else and then there's humor on
the other side where you've like really
accepted the pain and tragedy and made
friends with reality and there's a
freedom and lightness that comes after
you have that sense of acceptance um and
that's kind of how I've how I felt with
my conversations on my podcast some of
them have this really really serious
tone and then others just feel so much
more playful and light mmm and it's all
it's all great like I love I love it all
and I'm just I'm grateful for that that
humor that can that could come online
and shine through because I feel like it
is more me um yeah this sort of
eccentric playful personality it feels
more true to my essence mm and in how do
you select your guests like
in a way sometimes I'll hear a guest on
on someone else's podcast and be like oh
I'm swiping this guest like this person
is too good great um and sometimes it'll
be like I'll just read a tweet or
sometimes I'll read an article a medium
and you feel really drawn to this
particular person I saw that you had
Steven Jenkinson on your podcast
recently I haven't listened to it yet
but I look forward to it yeah but he I
found out about him because my family
read die wise which is one of his books
for I was like a family book club last
summer and we had like this whole family
retreat all around death and dying and
after I read that book I just
immediately emailed him to reach out to
see if you'd come and it it like took a
few months because he's really busy but
eventually we had this our scheduled so
sometimes it's sometimes there there it
takes a couple months for it to just
stayed and for them to get back to me
that's what happened with Charles
Eisenstein to these like really big
named really busy people all like put
out a signal and then it'll be a few
months later and then we'll have this
we'll finally have this conversation and
then the impetus for asking them will
have changed because I'll be different
in a few months and the conversation
will be will feel a lot different than
it would have if we had had the
conversation right away yes it's
interesting and one thing that's lovely
about having a podcast is that remember
when I was more in consumer mode and I I
mean then every sense of the word when I
was just watching the world in a way and
you go in a book Stirling was amazing
author blah blah and then it's like
almost like I got my status through
knowing about them and talking about
them to other people right
but now having a podcast like can I see
a book a new book I like oh I probably
can get them on my podcast if I every
shouts them if I wanted to collect them
so the optionality I've actually having
conversations with these people just
increased not that I want to have
conversations with everyone which is
sort of like that is there now which is
sort of a delicious
delicious feeling yeah yeah great yeah
yeah I'm wanting to get more more
movement embodiment people on my podcast
these days since that is sort of the the
direction I've been heading with my
energy trying to eat Oporto on my
podcast
who's that are you familiar with him no
no he's this um I might know him by face
or something
yeah he's this this Israeli guy who
studied many different movement
techniques capoeira being one of them
this sort of Brazilian dance martial art
mixture and his movement is he basically
one just wanted to study the first
principles of movement like why you
would move in the first place and what's
the what's the point of it and his whole
thing is about is about context so
training your system to be able to move
effectively in any given context so this
is different than say bodybuilding where
it's aesthetic focused where it's all
about the pump it's all about the the
building of muscle and you see these
like massive bodybuilders who sort of
all of that that principle to its
logical conclusion they're actually not
that effective of movers like if you if
you asked one of these giant
bodybuilders to help you like I don't
know like I'll help you move your couch
or something they may not actually be as
good at it because they've been focusing
on the muscles that are loose there is
that aesthetics so you know poor tall
stuff is like how can you be the most
effective sort of maximize your
kinesthetic intelligence across any
given context it's all about play
beginner's mind
it feels very sort of there's a lot of
Eastern philosophy that feels that it
gets sort of integrated into his his
philosophy hmm
I have a desire to ask you for advice so
the going back to when I first saw you
dancing on Twitter right like there's a
tension there for me experiencing that a
because like I said it just didn't fit
my mental model of you
you know like Collins the podcaster guy
that's in the sense making babies not
dancing why is he doing this right so
that was kind of like a confusing thing
and then there was a judgement
associated on my end seeing that all
right it was it was a subtle adjustment
judgement there and feeling into that
judgment now I don't have it now but
feeling into what that judgement was it
was almost maybe a jealousy or that's
maybe too strong of a word but it's like
I can't do that
or there's a belief that I can't do that
and I've ever wrote about this in the
the daily meditation Journal I'm doing
it's like the closest thing I've ever
come to dancing was I going to like
these awkward indie rock concerts and
just bobbing my head you know like being
self-conscious and I remember the first
existential dance party I was with my
wife and we were like self-consciously
dancing and I just felt like the
self-consciousness do every single
movement and then the second one I was
by myself and I just let it go you know
like like I let my body go and I still
felt the self-consciousness but I like I
there was moments where just went away
and then in my head I'm like well I'm
doing pretty good I'm not like I'm doing
dancing pretty well and then I watched
the video of of the recording I just
kept doing this like weird fish move I
call God the guide so I guess the
question is it could be multiple
questions here is like how to get over
that self-consciousness that's not the
right question the question I want to
ask and it's probably the wrong question
is is this how do I be a better dancer
mmm
hmm well I think I think you're on the
right track because I think that
curiosity is the is the place to start
and and like what I heard you say when
you're talking about this was there was
there were moments where you were sort
of surrendering to your own the
experience of your body letting your
body Drive and then the
self-consciousness would come back it's
sort of like um like a meditation
practice you know moving your thoughts
your thoughts start to arise
the move isn't to be like oh fuck now
I'm thinking dammit dammit dammit its to
notice the thoughts they're there and
then let them go so yeah maybe maybe
it's to to treat the experience like an
embodied meditation and the experience
of just open awareness to me it feels
very similar to the experience of
letting my body move in the way that it
wants to move
and I've been experimenting with this
this piece that's like um difference and
repetition so repetition is finding a
pattern so finding some sort of movement
sequence that feels good and that you
and that you can say okay I have this
down maybe it's some footwork maybe it's
doing something with your with your arms
maybe it's swaying back and forth
it's a pattern and you repeat it so the
repetition this is kind of like a mantra
it's sort of anchoring you into this
experience that's like okay I can do
this this is what I can do and then the
difference piece is when you feel moved
to disrupt the pattern and have
something new emerge something new and
creative mmm so it's kind of this
oscillation between emergent creativity
and step-by-step mastery which starts
with small patterns
that's really cool and this is I mean as
far as like teaching people how to be
better dancers this is like where I'm at
this is the edge of my this is like the
edge of my thinking because I really do
want how to figure out how to teach
dance in a way that isn't just teaching
choreography because I'm not really that
interested in that and I think this is I
don't I don't know what's out there
actually but I think this is a really
good intersection like this idea sex
between you know like kind of like
embodiment trauma release you know
choreography all combined together
creativity and then in your your digital
dance studio that you'll be opening up
soon if like if you had a course like I
would definitely take it um yeah what
would um what would you want from from a
dance course like other than just I want
to be a better dancer like if you had to
be more specific well I guess by the end
of the course I could go to an
existential dance party and feel fully
there and also look good while doing it
it's like it I guess that would be the
learning objective of the course I want
to take and I think that's I actually
think that's important I think it's
important to feel to look good while
you're doing a thing yeah it's not the
only thing but like vanity is a
perfectly good motivation for doing a
thing yeah I agree
not the only reason but like why not I
draw wants to look and feel good yeah
it's like having a relationship with
that like not denying what you just said
right and I think when you deny what
what you just said then you start having
an unhealthy relationship and you're
doing it anyways but you pretend you're
not doing it I'm I shut up right yeah
yeah yeah no I totally agree with that
so in addition to that learning
objective yeah just the practicals of it
I like the idea like giving the person
like some kind of like dance step or
something right like giving him a series
of that and then maybe having exercises
and how to break it so they just like
training wheels in a way that would be
really helpful and it could be like you
like just I remember my friend a Lube
Ameer ours off the guy who did in shadow
mm-hmm yeah you know that filmed in
shadow that everyone was like yeah he's
a fucking amazing dancer like he should
have a video of him dancing like huh
it's like again like you know like yeah
he's the animator guy then he knows that
I dance and then I asked how you should
learn how to dance and then he basically
like just copied asurs moves right like
he did I should move he's copying it in
the his house like watching videos and
he went to practice a nightclub and he
kept doing that back and forth and he
became like an amazing dancer from it
yeah yeah
but if you can somehow like take that
method and like make it accessible make
it fun you know make it like a really
good gesturing towards communitas I
think that'd be a really really cool
thing yeah yeah I think a good I think a
good first step might be to invite a few
choreographers that are really good at
transmitting moves have them on the
digital dance studio so I can actually
learn some pedagogical techniques from
them along with everybody else
yes it's I think us being podcasters
really it really lends itself for being
a steward of these kind of digital
spaces because like it's a it's a
humbling experience talking to Jordan
Hall for example right because like okay
the guy is the crazy iq is intelligent
like but I don't need to be at his level
that way I can just have to ask
facilitate by asking the questions and
it's the same thing with being a Stewart
you don't have to be the person that
engineers everything but you just have
to be good enough to speak to someone
else's day long and if you have a
relationship with your own day when you
ever relationship with their day one and
then you just tease it out kind of like
what we're doing right now
so yeah I think I think the pollak part
especially the meta podcasting is that
skillset if it's finally useful for
something right like
um I think it lends itself to that yeah
so I don't ask you something about this
existential dance party sure what is
what is something an experience a
feeling a sensation that you would like
to explore that we haven't already whoo
it's a good question hoof
[Music]
you know I have been having this kind of
like um like romantic like kind of
lovestruck romantic by going on the last
couple of days like I like you know when
you you have like zero game and you have
like a crush on someone in high school
that type of feeling right like that's
coming up for some reason right now in
my life and so that's something that's
that's alive and I'd like to kind of
lean into that a little bit more feeling
to it sink into it there's also kind of
like that warrior energy that thumos
right cuz I don't know if you listen to
the last situational assessment at the
store with Jordan Hall and then he said
that like he was talking about basically
like the pair the parasite sociopaths
that are like fucking up you know
Society of you gave me and then how
there's there's like evil men
essentially a little small minority of
them and then there's a lot of weak men
and then what we have to do with weak
men is position them so they actually
make the right choice as the wisest
choices and we got to get the evil men
of the picture he system like we got to
burn the fucking house down and just
like fucking do mos just like like a
rose to my body like that desire for
like like like wise domination in a way
right so and I that always come to I
always have that sort of energy coming
up but I'm never really kind of
successfully channeled it and then just
kind of like so I'd like to get a good
relationship with that yes I love that
yeah yeah there's definitely going to be
a few most warrior Oh
[Laughter]
maybe we should steam them like
existential dance parties to most
sections dance party oh yeah
lovestruck yeah it would be cool to have
an orienting theme yeah
so people are sort of people have like
maybe that word maybe like someone sees
existential dance party Lumos and
they're like oh what's the most and they
look it up and they start reading about
it and it elicits something in them
there so it's priming their experience
before they walk in there might be
something that's powerful about that
yeah and when I was thinking too it's
like so this is still was getting like
more people come like we the guy saying
sock event I was like a hundred people
RSVP'd Yancy strickler's having the
crowd of over 100 on Thursday and so I
imagine more attention is gonna go to
the existential dance party another kind
of these psycho technologies there I
imagine you're gonna have multiple ones
and your your studio as well and it
would be good to have a theme I imagine
because it's like selection bias it's
like yeah I don't really need to do most
right now I'm good there so they're not
they're gonna opt out of it but then the
people who can do it or want to do it or
feel like there's something calling them
you know they get selected for they get
called towards it so I I do think the
selection bias thing is pretty cool
there with having a theme on it yeah yes
okay cool I like that she's so she's
gonna be through Moss I leave it up to
you my friend legit that's your damon
the guide you there i'm good for
anything really is I trust you're just
servant on where this is guiding you so
I'm I'm just looking forward for the
next one come on yeah cool man
and so we're reaching to our mark is
there anything else you want to close
off with yeah I just want to thank you
man this is like that you're just um
you I think are leading by example of
what it what it looks like to to trust
that that Dame on and to create from
that space and and people can see like
what fruit is coming from it
and I and I think that's it's really
important to have to model that right
now and so yeah I just want to thank you
for doing it thanks man yeah will
receive the compliment yeah it's some
interesting times
you know mmm it's like III I I think I
told you before so I can't think in
first principles anymore you know I
can't reason that way
structure the world guide my life
through like just reason I'm reasoning I
still I still ground myself and prudence
but it's like it's reasonable not to be
reasonable in a way right and in in this
kind of complex chaotic ontology so I
essentially just handed the keys over to
the de Mond or what I call the game one
and then let's see where it takes me
I Ross or whatever great totally cool
man
so the next existential dance party is
8:30 p.m. Eastern Time this Thursday and
then I have regular ones at 7:30 same
time are same day and yeah calm and
thanks so much for coming on
yeah thank you Peter be well talk to you
soon yes woman